Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/briandhkim (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

Python

Scala

Languages

Korean

Spanish

English

Brian Kim

Software Engineer at DoorDash

San Francisco, California, United States

Summary

I am a full stack developer with a keen interest in building scalable backend systems, and delivering reliable solutions to prevalent user problems. My past/present endeavors and experiences include working with Java, Go, Scala, Cassandra, Akka, Python, Dask, Spark, Kafka, Jenkins, AWS, React, Angular, Docker, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, DevOps, and CI/CD.

I aim to find opportunities that will add new perspective on how technology can positively impact everyday life, and enhance my engineering versatility / agile teamwork skills.

Experience

DoorDash Software Engineer December 2020 - Present (2 years 10 months) New York, New York, United States

Capital One

3 years 6 months

Software Engineer, Senior Associate July 2018 - December 2020 (2 years 6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Built a depository for account transaction data with Cassandra data modeling, supporting a banking platform API in Go for querying transactions and saving account update for dependent processes via Kafka stream
- Implemented a data ecosystem platform using Python, Dask, Spark, and Kubernetes, allowing real-time and batch operations to extract data of business value to consume for computation of innovative features and machine learning models
- Expanded the credit card offer upsell/downsell mapping capabilities for the counteroffer micro-service, using CRUD operations to orchestrate flow between UI and backend using Java, RDS, MongoDB, and React

- Optimized the task execution performance of the Credit Scoring Microservice- a highly scalable, asynchronous service that executes risk and spend machine learning models to determine an applicant's credit worthiness in real-time, using Java, Scala, and Akka
- Coordinated with data scientists to build reusable workflows in a distributed acyclic graph to chain models of same business logic
- Designed and built the CI/CD system for deploying each model as its own containerized service using Flask API to remove the monolithic deployment of models and allow independent auto-scaling that is tailored to model-specific traffic load with Jenkins, AWS
- Reduced costs by 18% after calibrating efficient EC2/ECS resource reservation using CloudWatch CPU and memory utilization metrics

Associate Software Engineer July 2017 - June 2018 (1 year) San Francisco Bay Area

- Implemented the DevExchange API registration portal UI with Angular, React, JavaScript, and Node.js
- Revamped the Tools Marketplace UI, allowing users to on-board and consume inner-sourced enterprise tools, and receive real-time updates from starred tools
- Designed and built scalable CI/CD systems using AWS ECS, with decoupled components, multi-AZ RDS deployments, and active-active failover
- Developed real-time notifications and single sign-on functionality for Caliper- a JavaScript service that provides common utility services across the DevExchange platform

Capital One Software Engineering Intern June 2016 - August 2016 (3 months)

- Implemented a cloud self-service tools garage using Apache Mesos, Marathon, and Kubernetes
- Created unique Dockerfiles to build Docker images for various open source tools
- Constructed a web application using Node.js, Python, and AngularJS to allow users to customize and assemble JSON applications for groups of Docker containers they need, and to deploy them using Marathon and Kubernetes API calls

Diligence Vault Corp.

Software Developer Intern June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)

New York, NY

- Launched an investor due-diligence web interface
- Applied combinations of D3, Less, AngularJS and Bootstrap to create a personalized homepage with newsfeed
- · Built a Python web scraper to populate company background data

Capital One

Software Engineering Intern June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

- Developed a web interface which retrieved and reformatted AJAX JSON data into a user friendly format
- Supported multiple RESTful APIs across other servers and frameworks with different JSON schemas

Jayone Foods Inc Data Analyst Intern June 2010 - August 2010 (3 months) Paramount, CA

- Prepared Microsoft Access and Excel layouts to predict trends in sales pattern
- Delegated biweekly presentations with statistics of net profits and losses
- Oversaw quantitative interactions with international companies for imports and exports

Education

Arnold O. Beckman High School

Carnegie Mellon University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Electrical and Computer Engineering

Activity

09/13/2023, Viewed by Joeri Leemans